HECTOR FELIX

website: hector-felix.github.io m: (619) 400-7316 hector.getEmail@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/hector-felix



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Vision-driven software engineer with a proven record of powering operational excellence using technology, data analysis and management paradigms to achieve maximum impacts for leading organizations. Detail-oriented professional with keen interpersonal, communication and organization skills, as well as software development, implementation, and design expertise. Demonstrated passion for Defense and Space Systems, contributing to the next wave of innovation with dedication and creativity.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Natural Curiosity and Eagerness to Learn
- Big-Picture Thinking
- Business Intelligence

- Design and Testing
- Versatile, Fast-paced
- Technophile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Development and Implementation

Savvy Problem-Solving Skills

Software Data Analysis

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | RAYTHEON TECHNOLOGIES, COLLINS AEROSPACE, LOS ANGELES, CA, FEB. 2021 – PRESENT

- Ship software solutions within Military Avionics and Helicopters, Tactical, Communication, and Maintenance Applications.
- Build automated testing scripts (unit, integration, system) in Python using a TDD framework.
- Participate in daily, agile sprints/daily scrum to efficiently meet critical deadlines with minimum resource expenditures.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, OPERATIONS | Rush49 / Trolion Apps Inc., El Segundo, CA, Oct. 2014 – Feb. 2021

- Engineered and launched a conversational Chatbot which draws upon a knowledge base and reliance factor to reply to users in real-time.
- Implemented front- and back-end features and processes that increased user traffic by 30 % using applied business intelligence; redesigned the customer account page to include features such as email subscription preferences, payment profile, contact support option.
- Decreased fraud by 50% by implementing fraud detection suite. Developed a live ticketing integration using Galaxy Connect API.
- Integrated live, timed ticketing with various partners utilizing Galaxy Connect API.

BRANCH MANAGER, SENIOR TAX ANALYST | H&R BLOCK, CORONADO, CA, OCT. 2013 - OCT. 2014

- Fostered a collaborative and results-driven office culture using positive recognition, team initiatives, and mentorship.
- Consulted with clients to create a comprehensive tax plan for all situations and economic status.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING/SCRIPTING LANGUAGES:

- Proficient in C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL
- **Knowledgeable** in C, C#, Ada, HTML, CSS3, .NET
- Familiar with GO, PHP, Ruby, Swift, TypeScript, GraphQL

TECHNOLOGIES: RESTful APIs, MERN Stack

- JavaScript React.jS, Node.jS, Express.jS, Gatsby, jQuery
- Python Django, TensorFlow, PyTorch, NumPy, Keras, Pandas
- **Java** Hibernate, Spring, JDBC, Apache, Junit

TOOLS: Systems Architecture, MongoDB, Express.jS, React.jS, Node.jS (MERN Stack), Java Web Development, MySQL, Postgre SQL, Amazon Web Services(AWS), Heroku Cloud Services, GitHub, Continuous Integration, Microservices Architecture, Docker/Kubernetes, Maven/Atlassian, Bootstrap, Agile, UNIX, Beyond Compare, DOORS, PREP Peer Review, MatLab, LabView, SIL Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, NetBeans, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, Atom, MySQL, Xcode, ML applications, Neural Networks, Deep Learning, Git, JIRA, Jenkins

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, AUGUST 2020 (GPA: 3.5/4.0) | CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, DOMINGUEZ HILLS

Relevant Coursework: Analysis of Algorithms, Software Engineering, Data Structures, Programming Languages, Operating Systems

RELEVANT PROJECT WORK & OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

SERVERLESS PORTFOLIO APPLICATION (AWS REST API) | LIVE APPLICATION

- AWS Resources: Lambda Functions, API Gateway, DynamoDB, Amazon S3; SAM CLI, AWS CLI, Node.jS, REST APIs
- Postman to aid in the API building process and automate testing of different HTTP methods against my API (GET, POST, PUT, DELETE)

CHATBOT, HOUSTON SPACE CENTER (PYTHON) | GITHUB | DEMO | FRAMEWORKS: TENSORFLOW, NATURAL LANGUAGE TOOLKIT, NUMPY

Leveraged machine learning, deep learning & neural networks to relay responses based on a confidence factor.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION - LANGUAGES: SPANISH; INTERESTS: TRAVELING, HIKING, SPACE EXPLORATION, FANTASY FOOTBALL, CHELSEA FC, BASKETBALL